<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Language | Freelance .NET Web Developer in Mumbai]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.abhishekluv.in/blog/categories/language/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.abhishekluv.in/"/>
  <updated>2015-07-26T23:27:44+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://www.abhishekluv.in/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Abhishek Luv]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Learning Python Programming Language]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.abhishekluv.in/blog/2014/06/04/learning-python-programming-language/"/>
    <updated>2014-06-04T12:25:59+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://www.abhishekluv.in/blog/2014/06/04/learning-python-programming-language</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hello folks,</p>

<p>This week I have started learning the Python Programming Language through an online course offered by the University of Michigan via Coursera.org.</p>

<p>The course is intended for beginners and people who are interested in learning the Python Programming Language.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Here are some details about the course :</p>

<h3>About the Course</h3>

<p>This course is specifically designed to be a first programming course using the popular Python programming language. The pace of the course is designed to lead to mastery of each of the topics in the class. We will use simple data analysis as the programming exercises through the course. Understanding how to process data is valuable for everyone regardless of your career. This course might kindle an interest in more advanced programming courses or courses in web design and development or just provide skills when you are faced with a bunch of data that you need to analyze. You can do the programming assignments for the class using a web browser or using your personal computer. All required software for the course is free.</p>

<h3>Course Syllabus</h3>

<ul>
<li>Week One: Introduction &ndash; Why we program?</li>
<li>Week Two: Variables and Expressions</li>
<li>Week Three: Conditional code</li>
<li>Week Four: Functions</li>
<li>Week Five: Loops and Iteration</li>
<li>Week Six: Strings</li>
<li>Week Seven: Files</li>
<li>Week Eight: Lists</li>
<li>Week Nine: Dictionaries</li>
<li>Week Ten: Tuples</li>
<li>Optional Topic: Regular Expressions</li>
</ul>


<h3>Course Format</h3>

<p>Each week there will be about an hour of lecture material. The ten weeks of the course match the first ten chapters of the book &ndash; we cover one chapter per week.   Each week there will be some combination of a quiz, programming assignment, and/or an optional extra credit assignment.</p>

<p>Want to learn the Python Programming Language..<a href="https://www.coursera.org/course/pythonlearn">Join Here</a></p>

<p>Happy Learning..</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
