<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Sanskrit-mantra | Abhishek Luv]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.abhishekluv.in/blog/categories/sanskrit-mantra/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.abhishekluv.in/"/>
  <updated>2016-02-03T06:26:03+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://www.abhishekluv.in/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Abhishek Luv]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sanskrit Chants &amp; Prayers to Calm Ones Mind]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.abhishekluv.in/blog/2014/12/20/sanskrint-chants-and-prayers-to-calm-ones-mind/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-20T17:21:53+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://www.abhishekluv.in/blog/2014/12/20/sanskrint-chants-and-prayers-to-calm-ones-mind</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Guru Paduka Stotram is a very powerful chant that glorifies the &#8220;sandals of the Guru,&#8221; which are symbolically represented as &#8220;the boat to help cross the endless ocean of life.&#8221; This chant enables one to become receptive to the Guru&#8217;s Grace.</p>


<p>Listening to &ldquo;Guru Paduka Stotram&rdquo; chant my mind becomes relaxed and calm.</p>




<!-- more -->


<p></p>

<p><strong>Guru Paduka Stotram &ndash; Audio</strong></p>


<iframe width="100%" height="300" scrolling="no" frameborder="no" src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/89247675&amp;auto_play=false&amp;hide_related=false&amp;show_comments=true&amp;show_user=true&amp;show_reposts=false&amp;visual=true"></iframe>


<p><strong>Guru Paduka Stotram &ndash; Video</strong></p>


<iframe width="800" height="500" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/LAD9xlAodD8" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<p><strong>Guru Paduka Stotram &ndash; Lyrics</strong></p>


<p>1</p>


<blockquote><p>Anantha samsara samudhra thara naukayithabhyam guru bhakthithabhyam,
Vairagya samrajyadha poojanabhyam, namo nama sri guru padukhabyam., 1</p>
<p>Salutations and Salutations to the sandals of my Guru,
Which is a boat, which helps me,cross the endless ocean of life,
Which endows me, with the sense of devotion to my Guru,
And by worship of which, I attain the dominion of renunciation</p></blockquote>


<p>2</p>


<blockquote><p>Kavithva varasini sagarabhyam, dourbhagya davambudha malikabhyam,
Dhoorikrutha namra vipathithabhyam,, namo nama sri guru padukhabyam., 2
Salutations and Salutations to the sandals of my Guru,</p>
<p>Which is the ocean of knowledge, resembling the full moon,
Which is the water, which puts out the fire of misfortunes,
And which removes distresses of those who prostrate before it.</p></blockquote>


<p>3</p>


<blockquote><p>Natha yayo sripatitam samiyu kadachidapyasu daridra varya,
Mookascha vachaspathitham hi thabhyam,namo nama sri guru padukhabyam.3
Salutations and Salutations to the sandals of my Guru,</p>
<p>Which make those who prostrate before it,
Possessors of great wealth, even if they are very poor,,
And which makes even dumb people in to great orators.</p></blockquote>


<p>4</p>


<blockquote><p>Naleeka neekasa pada hrithabhyam, nana vimohadhi nivarikabyam,
Nama janabheeshtathathi pradhabhyam namo nama sri guru padukhabyam., 4</p>
<p>Salutations and Salutations to the sandals of my Guru,
Which attracts us, to lotus like feet of our Guru,
Which cures us, of the unwanted desires,
And which helps fulfill the desires of those who salute.</p></blockquote>


<p>5</p>


<blockquote><p>Nrupali mouleebraja rathna kanthi sariddha raja jjashakanyakabhyam,
Nrupadvadhabhyam nathaloka pankhthe, namo nama sri guru padukhabyam., 5</p>
<p>Salutations and Salutations to the sandals of my Guru,
Which shine like gems on the crown of a king,
Which shine like a maid in the crocodile infested stream,
And which make the devotees attain the status of a king.</p></blockquote>


<p>6</p>


<blockquote><p>Papandhakara arka paramparabhyam, thapathryaheendra khageswarabhyam,
Jadyadhi samsoshana vadaveebhyam namo nama sri guru padukhabyam., 6</p>
<p>Salutations and Salutations to the sandals of my Guru,
Which is like a series of Suns, driving away the dark sins,
Which is like the king of eagles, driving away the cobra of miseries,
And which is like a terrific fire drying away the ocean of ignorance.</p></blockquote>


<p>7</p>


<blockquote><p>Shamadhi shatka pradha vaibhavabhyam,Samadhi dhana vratha deeksithabhyam,
Ramadhavadeegra sthirha bhakthidabhyam, namo nama sri guru padukhabyam.7</p>
<p>Salutations and Salutations to the sandals of my Guru,
Which endows us, with the glorious six qualities like sham,
Which gives the students ,the ability to go in to eternal trance,
And which helps to get perennial devotion to the feet of Vishnu.</p></blockquote>


<p>8</p>


<blockquote><p>Swarchaparana makhileshtathabhyam, swaha sahayaksha durndarabhyam,
Swanthachad bhava pradha poojanabhyam, namo nama sri guru padukhabyam., 8</p>
<p>Salutations and Salutations to the sandals of my Guru
Which bestows all desires of the serving disciples,
Who are ever involved in carrying the burden of service
And which helps the aspirants to the state of realization.</p></blockquote>


<p>9</p>


<blockquote><p>Kaamadhi sarpa vraja garudabhyam, viveka vairagya nidhi pradhabhyam,
Bhodha pradhabhyam drutha mokshathabhyam, namo nama sri guru padukhabyam., 9</p>
<p>Salutations and Salutations to the sandals of my Guru
Which is the Garuda,which drives away the serpent of passion,
Which provides one, with the treasure of wisdom and renunciation,
Which blesses one,with enlightened knowledge,
And blesses the aspirant with speedy salvation.</p></blockquote>


<p><a href="http://www.hindupedia.com/en/Guru_Paduka_stotram">Lyrics Courtesy</a></p>


<p><a href="http://www.ishafoundation.org/blog/lifestyle/music/mystic-chants-guru-paduka-stotram/">Audio and Video Courtesy</a></p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
