<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: 2014 | Abhishek Luv]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.abhishekluv.in/blog/categories/2014/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.abhishekluv.in/"/>
  <updated>2016-06-02T16:47:09+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://www.abhishekluv.in/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Abhishek Luv]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sanskrit Chants &amp; Prayers to Calm Ones Mind]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.abhishekluv.in/blog/2014/12/20/sanskrint-chants-and-prayers-to-calm-ones-mind/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-20T17:21:53+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://www.abhishekluv.in/blog/2014/12/20/sanskrint-chants-and-prayers-to-calm-ones-mind</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Guru Paduka Stotram is a very powerful chant that glorifies the &#8220;sandals of the Guru,&#8221; which are symbolically represented as &#8220;the boat to help cross the endless ocean of life.&#8221; This chant enables one to become receptive to the Guru&#8217;s Grace.</p>


<p>Listening to &ldquo;Guru Paduka Stotram&rdquo; chant my mind becomes relaxed and calm.</p>




<!-- more -->


<p></p>

<p><strong>Guru Paduka Stotram &ndash; Audio</strong></p>


<iframe width="100%" height="300" scrolling="no" frameborder="no" src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/89247675&amp;auto_play=false&amp;hide_related=false&amp;show_comments=true&amp;show_user=true&amp;show_reposts=false&amp;visual=true"></iframe>


<p><strong>Guru Paduka Stotram &ndash; Video</strong></p>


<iframe width="800" height="500" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/LAD9xlAodD8" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<p><strong>Guru Paduka Stotram &ndash; Lyrics</strong></p>


<p>1</p>


<blockquote><p>Anantha samsara samudhra thara naukayithabhyam guru bhakthithabhyam,
Vairagya samrajyadha poojanabhyam, namo nama sri guru padukhabyam., 1</p>
<p>Salutations and Salutations to the sandals of my Guru,
Which is a boat, which helps me,cross the endless ocean of life,
Which endows me, with the sense of devotion to my Guru,
And by worship of which, I attain the dominion of renunciation</p></blockquote>


<p>2</p>


<blockquote><p>Kavithva varasini sagarabhyam, dourbhagya davambudha malikabhyam,
Dhoorikrutha namra vipathithabhyam,, namo nama sri guru padukhabyam., 2
Salutations and Salutations to the sandals of my Guru,</p>
<p>Which is the ocean of knowledge, resembling the full moon,
Which is the water, which puts out the fire of misfortunes,
And which removes distresses of those who prostrate before it.</p></blockquote>


<p>3</p>


<blockquote><p>Natha yayo sripatitam samiyu kadachidapyasu daridra varya,
Mookascha vachaspathitham hi thabhyam,namo nama sri guru padukhabyam.3
Salutations and Salutations to the sandals of my Guru,</p>
<p>Which make those who prostrate before it,
Possessors of great wealth, even if they are very poor,,
And which makes even dumb people in to great orators.</p></blockquote>


<p>4</p>


<blockquote><p>Naleeka neekasa pada hrithabhyam, nana vimohadhi nivarikabyam,
Nama janabheeshtathathi pradhabhyam namo nama sri guru padukhabyam., 4</p>
<p>Salutations and Salutations to the sandals of my Guru,
Which attracts us, to lotus like feet of our Guru,
Which cures us, of the unwanted desires,
And which helps fulfill the desires of those who salute.</p></blockquote>


<p>5</p>


<blockquote><p>Nrupali mouleebraja rathna kanthi sariddha raja jjashakanyakabhyam,
Nrupadvadhabhyam nathaloka pankhthe, namo nama sri guru padukhabyam., 5</p>
<p>Salutations and Salutations to the sandals of my Guru,
Which shine like gems on the crown of a king,
Which shine like a maid in the crocodile infested stream,
And which make the devotees attain the status of a king.</p></blockquote>


<p>6</p>


<blockquote><p>Papandhakara arka paramparabhyam, thapathryaheendra khageswarabhyam,
Jadyadhi samsoshana vadaveebhyam namo nama sri guru padukhabyam., 6</p>
<p>Salutations and Salutations to the sandals of my Guru,
Which is like a series of Suns, driving away the dark sins,
Which is like the king of eagles, driving away the cobra of miseries,
And which is like a terrific fire drying away the ocean of ignorance.</p></blockquote>


<p>7</p>


<blockquote><p>Shamadhi shatka pradha vaibhavabhyam,Samadhi dhana vratha deeksithabhyam,
Ramadhavadeegra sthirha bhakthidabhyam, namo nama sri guru padukhabyam.7</p>
<p>Salutations and Salutations to the sandals of my Guru,
Which endows us, with the glorious six qualities like sham,
Which gives the students ,the ability to go in to eternal trance,
And which helps to get perennial devotion to the feet of Vishnu.</p></blockquote>


<p>8</p>


<blockquote><p>Swarchaparana makhileshtathabhyam, swaha sahayaksha durndarabhyam,
Swanthachad bhava pradha poojanabhyam, namo nama sri guru padukhabyam., 8</p>
<p>Salutations and Salutations to the sandals of my Guru
Which bestows all desires of the serving disciples,
Who are ever involved in carrying the burden of service
And which helps the aspirants to the state of realization.</p></blockquote>


<p>9</p>


<blockquote><p>Kaamadhi sarpa vraja garudabhyam, viveka vairagya nidhi pradhabhyam,
Bhodha pradhabhyam drutha mokshathabhyam, namo nama sri guru padukhabyam., 9</p>
<p>Salutations and Salutations to the sandals of my Guru
Which is the Garuda,which drives away the serpent of passion,
Which provides one, with the treasure of wisdom and renunciation,
Which blesses one,with enlightened knowledge,
And blesses the aspirant with speedy salvation.</p></blockquote>


<p><a href="http://www.hindupedia.com/en/Guru_Paduka_stotram">Lyrics Courtesy</a></p>


<p><a href="http://www.ishafoundation.org/blog/lifestyle/music/mystic-chants-guru-paduka-stotram/">Audio and Video Courtesy</a></p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Orchard CMS v1.9 Tutorials Coming Soon]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.abhishekluv.in/blog/2014/12/10/orchard-cms-v1-dot-9-tutorials-coming-soon/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-10T17:20:47+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://www.abhishekluv.in/blog/2014/12/10/orchard-cms-v1-dot-9-tutorials-coming-soon</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Orchard CMS 1.9 Tutorials Coming Soon.</p>


<p><strong>New Features in Orchard v1.9</strong></p>


<p><a href="https://www.udemy.com/orchard-cms-for-absolute-beginners/">Orchard CMS Beginners Course</a></p>




<!-- more -->


<p></p>

<ul>
<li>Draftable &amp; Indexable Widgets</li>
<li>Dynamic Forms</li>
<li>Dynamic Layouts</li>
<li>Audit Trail</li>
<li>New Caching Features</li>
<li>Better Localization</li>
<li>Culture Selector</li>
<li>Improved Workflows</li>
</ul>


<p><a href="https://www.udemy.com/orchard-cms-for-absolute-beginners/">more</a></p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Learn How to Host Unlimited Static Website for FREE : Udemy Course]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.abhishekluv.in/blog/2014/08/27/learn-how-to-host-unlimited-static-website-for-free-udemy-course/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-27T17:19:37+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://www.abhishekluv.in/blog/2014/08/27/learn-how-to-host-unlimited-static-website-for-free-udemy-course</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>
GitHub Pages are public webpages freely hosted and easily published through the GitHub website. You can create and publish them online using the Automatic Page Generator. If you prefer to work locally, you can use the GitHub for Mac and Windows apps.

<!-- more --> 

</p>


<p>
In this course you&#8217;ll learn how to host a static website using GitHub Pages at no cost. You&#8217;ll need to purchase your own Domain Name which costs around $10 to $12 yearly that&#8217;s it.
</p>




<p>
A lot of people who are scared to get their First Website online now can have their website online right away using GitHub Pages.
</p>


<p>
In this course you&#8217;ll learn the following things:
</p>


<ul>
<li>Getting Started with GitHub</li>
<li>How to create Repositories and Organizations</li>
<li>How to use GitHub Pages</li>
<li>Types of GitHub Pages</li>
<li>How to use the Git Extensions Software</li>
<li>How to Host Static Websites using GitHub Pages</li>
</ul>


<p>
<strong>Note : Course is about GitHub Pages only and not about Designing Websites. This course only covers the Hosting part and not Designing.</strong>
</p>


<p>
Thank You
</p>


<p>
Abhishek Luv
</p>


<p>
<strong>Happy Learning!</strong>
</p>


<p><a href="https://www.udemy.com/learn-how-to-host-static-websites-using-github-pages" target="_blank" class="btn btn-primary btn-lg">Join This Course</a></p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Welcome to Orchard Beginner]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.abhishekluv.in/blog/2014/07/26/welcome-to-orchard-beginner/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-26T17:17:51+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://www.abhishekluv.in/blog/2014/07/26/welcome-to-orchard-beginner</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Orchard Beginner</strong> is created with the aim to provide users and developers to have a Beginner&rsquo;s Guide to learn the ins and outs of Orchard.</p>


<p>We begin with the Basics of Orchard i.e. Talking about <strong>Basic site management</strong>, <strong>User management</strong> and then we step into more important features of Orchard like <strong>Queries</strong>, <strong>Projector</strong>, <strong>Taxonomies</strong>, <strong>Custom Forms</strong>, <strong>Workflows</strong> and <strong>Recipes</strong>.</p>




<!-- more -->


<p></p>

<p>After that we&rsquo;ll talk about how to <strong>Get Started</strong> with <strong>Theme Development</strong> in Orchard and later on <strong>Module Development</strong> too.</p>


<p>Again <strong>Welcome To Orchard Beginner</strong>.</p>


<p><a href="http://orchardbeginner.com/">Orchard Beginner</a></p>


<p><strong>Happy Orcharding!!</strong></p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Orchard CMS Tutorial : Recipes in Orchard CMS]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.abhishekluv.in/blog/2014/06/28/orchard-cms-tutorial-recipes-in-orchard-cms/"/>
    <updated>2014-06-28T17:16:45+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://www.abhishekluv.in/blog/2014/06/28/orchard-cms-tutorial-recipes-in-orchard-cms</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Recipes in Orchard are a huge productivity boost when installing Orchard CMS on a client&rsquo;s server,
because it avoids the Orchard Web Developer from having to manually configure Orchard CMS instance.</p>




<!-- more -->


<p></p>

<h2>What is a Recipe</h2>


<p>Orchard simplifies the process of setting up a new website by letting you use website recipes. A recipe is an XML file that contains the startup configuration for an Orchard website. When you start Orchard for the first time, you can select a recipe that best matches the type of site you want to set up.</p>


<p>For example, if you want your website to be a blog, you can select the Blog recipe, and much of the configuration work will be done for you.</p>


<p>You can create your own recipes and customize the process of setting a website and configuring Orchard features. Recipes can also instruct Orchard to download and install modules and themes from the Orchard Gallery during website setup.</p>


<p>This course describes how to use recipes, how to create custom recipes, export or import recipes, how to create a website using a custom recipe.</p>


<blockquote><p><em>docs.orchardproject.net</em></p></blockquote>


<p><a href="https://www.udemy.com/orchard-cms-tutorial-recipes-in-orchard-cms/" target="_blank" class="btn btn-primary btn-lg">Join This Course</a></p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
