<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Recipes | Freelance .NET Web Developer in Mumbai]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.abhishekluv.in/blog/categories/recipes/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.abhishekluv.in/"/>
  <updated>2015-07-28T11:52:56+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://www.abhishekluv.in/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Abhishek Luv]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Orchard Beginner : Recipes in Orchard]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.abhishekluv.in/blog/2014/09/22/orchard-beginner-recipes-in-orchard/"/>
    <updated>2014-09-22T16:31:54+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://www.abhishekluv.in/blog/2014/09/22/orchard-beginner-recipes-in-orchard</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Welcome to Orchard Beginner! Recipes is one of the most useful feature in Orchard. Orchard Recipes allow you to setup your site with additional pre-configured options, features and settings out of the box.</p>

<p>Orchard simplifies the process of setting up a new website by letting you use website recipes.</p>

<p>A recipe is an XML file that contains the start-up configuration for an Orchard website. When you start Orchard for the first time, you can select a recipe that best matches the type of site you want to set up.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Orchard CMS Tutorial : Recipes in Orchard CMS]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.abhishekluv.in/blog/2014/06/28/orchard-cms-tutorial-recipes-in-orchard-cms/"/>
    <updated>2014-06-28T17:55:34+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://www.abhishekluv.in/blog/2014/06/28/orchard-cms-tutorial-recipes-in-orchard-cms</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Recipes in Orchard are a huge productivity boost when installing Orchard CMS on a client&rsquo;s server,
because it avoids the Orchard Web Developer from having to manually configure Orchard CMS instance.</p>

<!-- more -->


<h2>What is a Recipe</h2>

<p>Orchard simplifies the process of setting up a new website by letting you use website recipes. A recipe is an XML file that contains the startup configuration for an Orchard website. When you start Orchard for the first time, you can select a recipe that best matches the type of site you want to set up.</p>

<p>For example, if you want your website to be a blog, you can select the Blog recipe, and much of the configuration work will be done for you.</p>

<p>You can create your own recipes and customize the process of setting a website and configuring Orchard features. Recipes can also instruct Orchard to download and install modules and themes from the Orchard Gallery during website setup.</p>

<p>This course describes how to use recipes, how to create custom recipes, export or import recipes, how to create a website using a custom recipe.</p>

<blockquote><p><em>docs.orchardproject.net</em></p></blockquote>

<p><a href="https://www.udemy.com/orchard-cms-tutorial-recipes-in-orchard-cms/" target="_blank" class="btn btn-primary btn-lg">Join This Course</a></p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
