<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Csharp-day2 | Abhishek Luv]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.abhishekluv.in/blog/categories/csharp-day2/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.abhishekluv.in/"/>
  <updated>2016-05-15T17:04:01+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://www.abhishekluv.in/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Abhishek Luv]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Learn C# in 7 Days : Day 2]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.abhishekluv.in/blog/2016/04/09/learn-csharp-in-7-days-day-2/"/>
    <updated>2016-04-09T16:08:02+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://www.abhishekluv.in/blog/2016/04/09/learn-csharp-in-7-days-day-2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Learning C# for beginners can be little difficult in the first place. But it isn&rsquo;t that difficult.</p>

<p>When starting to learn C# you should start with the basics and not get into the deep rabbit hole of it.</p>

<p>This is Day 2 of Learn C# in 7 Days. Checkout <a href="http://www.abhishekluv.in/blog/2016/04/09/learn-csharp-in-7-days-day-1/">Day 1</a> before starting with Day 2.</p>

<!-- more -->


<h2>Topics we&rsquo;ll be discussing</h2>

<ul>
<li>Classes</li>
<li>Objects</li>
<li>Constructor</li>
<li>Methods with returns values</li>
<li>Methods with Parameters and Arguments</li>
<li>This keyword</li>
<li>What is Object-Oriented Programming

<ul>
<li>Encapsulation</li>
<li>Polymorphism</li>
<li>Inheritance</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2>Classes</h2>

<p>A class is a template for creating an object.</p>

<pre><code>public class Employee
{
    // This is a constructor 
    public Employee()
    {

    }
    // This is the Data 
    public string Name;
    public int Age;

    // This is a method which performs actions on the data
    public void DisplayData()
    {
        Console.WriteLine(Name + Age);
    }
}
</code></pre>

<h2>Objects</h2>

<p>An Object is an instance of a class. In other word a snapshot or copy of a class having all the data and methods associated with it.</p>

<pre><code>public class Program
{
    static void Main()
    {
        Employee abhishekluv = new Employee();
        abhishekluv.DisplayData();
    }
}
</code></pre>

<p>The <code>new</code> keyword + <code>Employee()</code> the constructor <code>new Employee()</code> is used to create an object of a class i.e. an instance of a class.</p>

<h2>Constructor</h2>

<p>Every time you declare a class in C# there is a method <code>Public Employee()</code> created in the background automatically by the compiler having the same name as the class.</p>

<ul>
<li>Constructor is a method that has the same name as the class</li>
<li>Constructor is executed when an object is created</li>
<li>Constructor is used to set default/initial values for an object</li>
<li>Constructor doesn&rsquo;t return anything including <code>void</code></li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Play with the constructor</strong></p>

<pre><code>    public Employee()
    {
        Console.WriteLine("Constructor is fired");
    }
</code></pre>

<p><strong>Constructor with Parameters and Arguments</strong></p>

<p>For example: You have declared a class with two public variables and one public method.</p>

<p>As constructors are used to initial default values during object creation you can define those values using a parameterized constructor.</p>

<pre><code>class Employee
{
    public string Name;
    public int Age;

    public Employee()
    {
        Name = 6;
        Age = 5;

        Console.WriteLine("Ctor fired");
    }

    public Employee(string name, int age)
    {
        this.Name = name;
        this.Age = age;
    }
    public void DisplayData()
    {
        Console.WriteLine(Name + Age);
    }
}

// creating a new Employee object by calling the parameterized constructor
Employee abhishekluv = new Employee(3,4);
</code></pre>

<p>When an object of a class is created using the <code>new</code> keyword the constructor method is called to initialize values or get and set private variables using public method parameters and arguments.</p>

<p>In the above given example <code>public Employee(string name, int age)</code> is a parameterized constructor which has two parameters <code>string name</code> and <code>int age</code>.</p>

<h2>This keyword</h2>

<p><code>this</code> keyword is used to access the class level data members, variables and methods.</p>

<p>For example: In the above code, the <code>public Employee(string name, int age)</code> method takes in two arguments or data values for the two defined parameters <code>string name</code> and <code>int age</code>. At the time of object creation these values are applied to the member variables within the class using the this keyword <code>this.Name</code> and <code>this.Age</code>.</p>

<p>Why use <code>this</code> keyword? Because it makes it easy to differeniate between the declared method parameters and the class member variables with the same name. <code>name</code> is the parameter declared for the <code>DisplayData</code> methods and <code>this.Name</code> is used to access the class level member variables.</p>

<h2>Methods with returns values</h2>

<p>Ever wondered why the hell you keep seeing the <code>void</code> keyword everywhere when programming in C#.</p>

<p>Let&rsquo;s talk about it.</p>

<p>Every method performs actions using the data variables and members defined within a class. After performing those actions the method has to return the results of those actions or sometimes not return anything.</p>

<p><code>void</code> keyword is used when you don&rsquo;t want a method to return anything to the calling method/function. And when you want to return something using a method then you will have to specify the return data type of that method.</p>

<p><strong>Example:</strong></p>

<p><em>Note: Method names used in these examples are for educational purpose only. :P</em></p>

<pre><code>Public void IDontReturnAnything(){
    Console.WriteLine("Hello"); 
}

Public string IReturnAStringValue()
    return "Hello";
}

Public string IReturnAIntValue()
    return 143;
}
</code></pre>

<h2>Methods with Parameters and Arguments</h2>

<p>One or more variables declared with the Method Signature are called Parameters.</p>

<p>For example:</p>

<p><code>public double FindArea(int length, int width) { }</code></p>

<p>In the above given example <code>int length</code> and <code>int width</code> are parameters declared for the <code>FindArea()</code></p>

<p>When a method is declared with parameters then it means that method can accept input values or in other words it can accept arguments.</p>

<p>The values which we pass to method parameters are called <code>Arguments</code>.</p>

<p>While calling the <code>FindArea()</code> method we can pass the values as argument which the <code>FindArea()</code> method can use for processing like this <code>FindArea(3,4)</code>.</p>

<h2>this Keyword</h2>

<p><code>this</code> keyword in C# is used to access the class level members and data.</p>

<p>In a C# class there are different types of variables.</p>

<ul>
<li>Class level variables (Global to the whole class)</li>
<li>Method level parameter variables (Local to that method only which a method can return)</li>
</ul>


<p>For example:</p>

<p>You have declared a class level variable as <code>int age;</code> and method level parameter variable as <code>int age</code>.</p>

<p>To access class level age use <code>this.age</code> and for method level parameter variable use <code>age</code>.</p>

<pre><code>public class Employee
{
    public int age;

    // this is a parameterized constructor with age as parameter and initializing the class level age variable 
    // using the this keyword
    public Employee(int age)
    {
        // Here we are using this.age to access the class level variables and then assigning the input value of age
       // coming from the age parameter of the constructor
        this.age = age;
    }

    public DisplayEmployeeAage()
    {
        Console.WriteLine("Age is = " + age);
    }
}
</code></pre>

<h2>Object-Oriented Programming</h2>

<p>Any programming language which follows 3 rules of OOP is called a Object-Oriented Programming Language.</p>

<p><strong>Rules for OOP:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Encapsulation : Data Hiding</li>
<li>Polymorphism : Overloading and Overriding</li>
<li>Inheritance : Abstract classes and Interfaces</li>
</ul>


<p>Let&rsquo;s discuss each of these types in detail.</p>

<p><strong>Encapsulation</strong></p>

<p>Encapsulation is the concept of writing programs with data and methods that act on the data.</p>

<p>With encapsulation also comes another concept called Data Hiding. In data hiding we keep the data safe within the class and only accessible within the class. Now, that doesn&rsquo;t mean we wont be able to access the class data outside it. Yes we can access the data using public methods declared within a class.</p>

<p>Data hiding concept can be applied by using access modifiers in front of classes, member variables and methods.</p>

<p><em>Commonly used access modifiers:</em></p>

<ul>
<li>public : accessible at class, sub-class and project level</li>
<li>protected : accessible at class and sub-class level</li>
<li>private : accessible at class level only</li>
</ul>


<p>Example:</p>

<pre><code>public class Sample
{
    private int age;
    public int salary { get; private set; }

    public int DisplaySalary()
    {
        return this.salary;
    }

    public void SetData(int age, int salary)
    {
        this.age = age;
        this.salary = salary;
    }

    public void DisplayData()
    {
        Console.Write("age is = " + age);
        Console.Write("salary is = " + salary);
    }
}

public class TestSample
{
    static void Main()
    {
        Sample sample = new Sample();
        sample.SetData(2, 333);
        sample.DisplayData();

        //the age variable of the sample cannot be accessed here
        // is inaccessible due to protection level
        // sample.age;
        // this is encapsulation and data hiding

        Console.Write("\n");

        Console.Write("salary is = " + sample.DisplaySalary());

        Console.ReadLine();
    }
}
</code></pre>

<p>In order to implement data hiding we can use <code>getter</code> and <code>setter</code> to limited read and write access to a particular data member in a class.</p>

<p>In this example we have used <code>get</code> and <code>private set</code> for the salary property <code>public int salary { get; private set; }</code>.</p>

<p><code>get</code> means <code>salary</code> property can be accessed outside of the <code>Sample</code> class and <code>private set</code> means <code>salary</code> property data can be set within the <code>Sample</code> class only and not from outside of the class.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
