<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: 2016 | Abhishek Luv]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.abhishekluv.in/blog/categories/2016/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.abhishekluv.in/"/>
  <updated>2016-01-27T22:39:08+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://www.abhishekluv.in/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Abhishek Luv]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Orchard Beginner Module 1 : Getting Started (Completed)]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.abhishekluv.in/blog/2016/01/26/orchard-beginner-module-1-getting-started-completed/"/>
    <updated>2016-01-26T13:33:24+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://www.abhishekluv.in/blog/2016/01/26/orchard-beginner-module-1-getting-started-completed</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Orchard Beginner Module 1 : Getting Started completed.</p>

<p>Orchard CMS Tutorials brought to you by Orchard Beginner <a href="http://orchardbeginner.com/">http://orchardbeginner.com/</a></p>

<p><em>Note: As I had mentioned in one of my <a href="/blog/2015/12/21/plans-for-year-2016/">previous post</a> that I will be keeping track of every task I do and blog about it online.</em></p>

<!-- more -->




<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/CbBuiHj0Qkg?list=PL8AwaH3ssiATad095YNAoaIxHVkoh4Yky" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>




<p>New to Orchard CMS?</p>


<p>Orchard CMS is a free, open source, community-focused Content Management System built on the ASP.NET MVC platform.</p>


<p>Orchard is delivered under the .NET Foundation <a href="http://www.dotnetfoundation.org/orchard">http://www.dotnetfoundation.org/orchard</a>. For more info on Orchard visit the official website <a href="http://www.orchardproject.net/">http://www.orchardproject.net/</a>
and for more Orchard CMS tutorials subscribe to <a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCAQxeMbUaKePrVE3wbNZxjg">our Orchard Beginner YouTube channel</a> or bookmark Orchard Beginner website for future reference.</p>


<p>Stay tuned.</p>

<p>Take care!</p>

<p>Abhishek Luv</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Standing and Sitting With Pomodoro Technique]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.abhishekluv.in/blog/2016/01/13/standing-and-sitting-with-pomodoro-technique/"/>
    <updated>2016-01-13T17:31:42+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://www.abhishekluv.in/blog/2016/01/13/standing-and-sitting-with-pomodoro-technique</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Standing and Sitting with Pomodoro Technique.</p>

<p>This week I decided to experiment and make a custom standing desk for myself.</p>




<!-- more -->




<p><em>As I had mentioned in one of my <a href="http://www.abhishekluv.in/blog/2015/12/21/plans-for-year-2016/">previous post</a> that I will be keeping track of every task I do and blog about it online.</em></p>




<p>At this moment the setup looks quite messy with a lot of wires hanging around.</p>




<h2>Things used to setup the standing desk</h2>




<p><em>Only two things.</em></p>




<ul>
<li>A Wooden adjustable study table</li>
<li>Some books to adjust the height of the wooden study table</li>
</ul>




<h2>Cost</h2>




<p>Just 900/- INR i.e. $15</p>




<p><img src="" data-src="http://s3-ap-southeast-1.amazonaws.com/d2dstaticresources/abhishek/Standing+Desk.JPG" title="Abhishek Luv's Custom Standing Desk" alt="&quot;Abhishek Luv's Custom Standing Desk&quot;" /></p>


<p>Why a standing desk? Because too much of sitting is bad.</p>

<h2>What happens if you stand too much?</h2>

<ul>
<li>It can cause leg pain</li>
<li>It can cause back pain</li>
<li>It can make your legs sore</li>
</ul>


<h2>What happens if you sit too much?</h2>

<ul>
<li>It can affect the flow of blood and oxygen in your body</li>
<li>It can become the cause of your obesity</li>
<li>It can cause you headaches, legs, arms and wrist numbness</li>
</ul>


<p>We need to strike a balance between standing, sitting and doing activities like stretching, squatting, doing vital deep diaphragmatic breathing, and drinking plenty of water which can help us lose those fat sitting on our belly.</p>

<p>Ever heard of Pomodoro technique?</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s a technique where you work with time and not against time by taking short breaks in between while doing your work.</p>

<p>It can help you manage distractions and create a better work/life balance.</p>

<p>Now should we stand or sit while working? It&rsquo;s not a question about standing or sitting. Moving more is probably better than standing or sitting.</p>

<h2>Better solution</h2>

<p>A better solution is to use Pomodoro technique with standing and sitting while working.</p>

<p>Example:</p>

<ul>
<li>Standing for 25mins and Sitting for 5mins</li>
<li>Sitting for 50mins and Standing for 10mins</li>
<li>Note: Don&rsquo;t forget to include squatting and stretching and having plenty of water while you stand or sit</li>
</ul>


<p>The key is to do some activity every day.</p>

<ul>
<li>A walk to and from work</li>
<li>or taking the stairs</li>
</ul>


<p>Stay healthy, Stay fit!</p>

<p>Stay tuned!</p>




<p>Take care!</p>




<p>Abhishek Luv</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My FitBit Badges]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.abhishekluv.in/blog/2016/01/09/my-fitbit-badges/"/>
    <updated>2016-01-09T07:24:46+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://www.abhishekluv.in/blog/2016/01/09/my-fitbit-badges</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Just a quick post to share my FitBit badges.</p>

<p>My fitbit badges starting from 13th December 2015.</p>

<p><em>As I had mentioned in one of my <a href="/blog/2015/12/21/plans-for-year-2016/">previous post</a> that I will be keeping track of every task I do and blog about it online.</em></p>

<!-- more -->




<p><img src="" data-src="http://s3-ap-southeast-1.amazonaws.com/abhishekluv/images/abhishek-luv-fitbit-badges.png" title="My FitBit Badeges" alt="My FitBit Badges" /></p>




<p><img src="" data-src="http://s3-ap-southeast-1.amazonaws.com/abhishekluv/images/abhishek-luv-fitibit-weekly-steps.jpg" title="MY FitBit Weekly Steps" alt="MY FitBit Weekly Steps" /></p>




<p><img src="" data-src="http://s3-ap-southeast-1.amazonaws.com/abhishekluv/images/abhishek-luv-fitbit-dashboard.png" title="FitBit Dashboard" alt="FitBit Dasboard" /></p>


<p><a href="/blog/2015/12/19/getting-healthy-fit-and-consistent/" title="Stay healthy, fit and in shape">Stay healthy, fit and in shape</a></p>

<p>Stay tuned!</p>

<p>Take care!</p>

<p>Abhishek Luv</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Decisions That Changed My Life]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.abhishekluv.in/blog/2016/01/06/decisions-that-changed-my-life/"/>
    <updated>2016-01-06T12:16:07+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://www.abhishekluv.in/blog/2016/01/06/decisions-that-changed-my-life</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Decisions That Changed My Life.</p>

<p>Focus == Feeling!</p>

<!-- more -->


<ul>
<li>Focusing on the Present and Self</li>
<li>What others think about me is none of my business</li>
<li>Learning to say yes to my Life and Dreams</li>
<li>Being mindful of my inner conversations and not allowing them to control me</li>
<li>Overcoming my fears</li>
<li>Not to become comfortable, satisfied and keep on hard working</li>
<li>Not to complain and blame others</li>
<li>Feeling worthy of myself</li>
<li>Not to procrastinate</li>
<li>Getting emotional fitness and psychological strength</li>
<li>Taking decisions as decision is the ultimate power that shapes destiny</li>
<li>Not to make excuses. Excusing is accusing</li>
<li>Having a courageous and a positive mind-set</li>
<li>Exploring my web i.e. mind, beliefs, emotions and spiritual dimensions that are controlling me</li>
</ul>


<p>I&rsquo;ll be adding more points to this list in the future.</p>

<p>Stay tuned!</p>

<p>Take care</p>

<p>Abhishek Luv</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Things Every Newbie Programmer Should Know & Do]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.abhishekluv.in/blog/2016/01/05/things-every-newbie-programmer-should-do/"/>
    <updated>2016-01-05T07:38:27+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://www.abhishekluv.in/blog/2016/01/05/things-every-newbie-programmer-should-do</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Things Every Newbie Programmer Should Know &amp; Do.</p>

<ul>
<li>Keep learning</li>
<li>Start learning from Open source projects</li>
<li>Read code</li>
<li>Do a lot of practice</li>
</ul>


<!-- more -->


<p><em>All of the points mentioned in this blog post are from the book I&rsquo;m currently reading &ldquo;97 Things Every Programmer Should Know&rdquo;.</em></p>

<p><em>As I was reading this book I just thought to share it on my blog for students and newbies who haven&rsquo;t read this book.</em></p>

<h2>Keep Learning</h2>

<p>To play it safe, you need to take responsibility for your own education. Don&rsquo;t try to depend on computer institutes and their fake stale certificates and degrees.</p>

<ul>
<li>Start reading books, blogs, twitter feeds, magazines and websites.</li>
<li>Get hands on by writing some code</li>
<li>Find yourself a mentor</li>
<li>Start fiddling with frameworks and libraries you use</li>
<li>A good way to learn something is to teach or speak about it</li>
<li>Join a local meetup group</li>
<li>Listen to developer podcasts</li>
<li>Learn a new language every year</li>
<li>Learn and understand the language</li>
</ul>


<p>Knowing how something works makes you know how to use it better.</p>

<h2>Start learning from Open source projects</h2>

<p>Getting started with open source is pretty easy.</p>

<ul>
<li>You can start by offering help to fix the documentation of an open source project</li>
<li>Read other people&rsquo;s code. You can learn a lot by reading other people&rsquo;s source code</li>
<li>You can contribute your own code and ideas to the projects</li>
<li>You will meet new like-minded people and become friends with them</li>
<li>Open source contributions can help you to add real-world experience in the technology that actually interests you</li>
<li>You can get community rewards, benefits and access to official project sites and documentation websites.</li>
</ul>


<p>In order to find more open sourced software’s, components and frameworks head over to github.com and search for projects according to your favourite programming language.</p>

<p>Once you have done searching and finding an interested project according to your requirement, next start learning, using and contributing to that project on GitHub.</p>

<p>And if you were not able to find any projects, then build your own project and share it with the world. If you really want to get involved with projects online, you could offer to help out with the documentation or you could start by volunteering to write test code.</p>

<p>Contributing, helping and fixing open source projects and documentation, finding bugs, suggesting fixes and making friends will make you a better programmer than who is not doing open source.</p>

<p>Now go out there and fix some projects and documentations.</p>

<h2>Read code</h2>

<p>Start reading other people&rsquo;s source code. Try to learn from other people&rsquo;s mistakes and get better at coding.</p>

<p>Now from where should you start?</p>

<p>Open source projects&hellip;</p>

<p>Open source projects are full of good examples of how to write brilliant and readable code.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s always better to read some source code instead of a book if you need to improve your programming skills.</p>

<h2>Do a lot of practice</h2>

<p>you need Skills and Techniques to become good at something especially programming and with a lot of practice you can become a skilled programmer.</p>

<p>You need 10,000 hours of practice i.e. 416 days and 16 hours of practice to become an expert.</p>

<p>Practicing does not mean doing what you are good at; it means challenging yourself, doing what you are not good at.</p>

<p>Practicing is about learning, learning that changes you, learning that makes you better at coding and improves your coding skills.</p>

<p><em>All of the points mentioned in this blog post are from the book I&rsquo;m currently reading &ldquo;97 Things Every Programmer Should Know&rdquo;.</em></p>

<p><em>As I was reading this book I just thought to share it on my blog for students and newbies who haven&rsquo;t read this book.</em></p>

<p>Stay tuned!</p>

<p>Take Care!</p>

<p>Abhishek Luv</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
