<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: 2016 | Abhishek Luv]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.abhishekluv.in/blog/categories/2016/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.abhishekluv.in/"/>
  <updated>2016-05-15T17:04:01+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://www.abhishekluv.in/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Abhishek Luv]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Learn C# in 7 Days : Day 2]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.abhishekluv.in/blog/2016/04/09/learn-csharp-in-7-days-day-2/"/>
    <updated>2016-04-09T16:08:02+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://www.abhishekluv.in/blog/2016/04/09/learn-csharp-in-7-days-day-2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Learning C# for beginners can be little difficult in the first place. But it isn&rsquo;t that difficult.</p>

<p>When starting to learn C# you should start with the basics and not get into the deep rabbit hole of it.</p>

<p>This is Day 2 of Learn C# in 7 Days. Checkout <a href="http://www.abhishekluv.in/blog/2016/04/09/learn-csharp-in-7-days-day-1/">Day 1</a> before starting with Day 2.</p>

<!-- more -->


<h2>Topics we&rsquo;ll be discussing</h2>

<ul>
<li>Classes</li>
<li>Objects</li>
<li>Constructor</li>
<li>Methods with returns values</li>
<li>Methods with Parameters and Arguments</li>
<li>This keyword</li>
<li>What is Object-Oriented Programming

<ul>
<li>Encapsulation</li>
<li>Polymorphism</li>
<li>Inheritance</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2>Classes</h2>

<p>A class is a template for creating an object.</p>

<pre><code>public class Employee
{
    // This is a constructor 
    public Employee()
    {

    }
    // This is the Data 
    public string Name;
    public int Age;

    // This is a method which performs actions on the data
    public void DisplayData()
    {
        Console.WriteLine(Name + Age);
    }
}
</code></pre>

<h2>Objects</h2>

<p>An Object is an instance of a class. In other word a snapshot or copy of a class having all the data and methods associated with it.</p>

<pre><code>public class Program
{
    static void Main()
    {
        Employee abhishekluv = new Employee();
        abhishekluv.DisplayData();
    }
}
</code></pre>

<p>The <code>new</code> keyword + <code>Employee()</code> the constructor <code>new Employee()</code> is used to create an object of a class i.e. an instance of a class.</p>

<h2>Constructor</h2>

<p>Every time you declare a class in C# there is a method <code>Public Employee()</code> created in the background automatically by the compiler having the same name as the class.</p>

<ul>
<li>Constructor is a method that has the same name as the class</li>
<li>Constructor is executed when an object is created</li>
<li>Constructor is used to set default/initial values for an object</li>
<li>Constructor doesn&rsquo;t return anything including <code>void</code></li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Play with the constructor</strong></p>

<pre><code>    public Employee()
    {
        Console.WriteLine("Constructor is fired");
    }
</code></pre>

<p><strong>Constructor with Parameters and Arguments</strong></p>

<p>For example: You have declared a class with two public variables and one public method.</p>

<p>As constructors are used to initial default values during object creation you can define those values using a parameterized constructor.</p>

<pre><code>class Employee
{
    public string Name;
    public int Age;

    public Employee()
    {
        Name = 6;
        Age = 5;

        Console.WriteLine("Ctor fired");
    }

    public Employee(string name, int age)
    {
        this.Name = name;
        this.Age = age;
    }
    public void DisplayData()
    {
        Console.WriteLine(Name + Age);
    }
}

// creating a new Employee object by calling the parameterized constructor
Employee abhishekluv = new Employee(3,4);
</code></pre>

<p>When an object of a class is created using the <code>new</code> keyword the constructor method is called to initialize values or get and set private variables using public method parameters and arguments.</p>

<p>In the above given example <code>public Employee(string name, int age)</code> is a parameterized constructor which has two parameters <code>string name</code> and <code>int age</code>.</p>

<h2>This keyword</h2>

<p><code>this</code> keyword is used to access the class level data members, variables and methods.</p>

<p>For example: In the above code, the <code>public Employee(string name, int age)</code> method takes in two arguments or data values for the two defined parameters <code>string name</code> and <code>int age</code>. At the time of object creation these values are applied to the member variables within the class using the this keyword <code>this.Name</code> and <code>this.Age</code>.</p>

<p>Why use <code>this</code> keyword? Because it makes it easy to differeniate between the declared method parameters and the class member variables with the same name. <code>name</code> is the parameter declared for the <code>DisplayData</code> methods and <code>this.Name</code> is used to access the class level member variables.</p>

<h2>Methods with returns values</h2>

<p>Ever wondered why the hell you keep seeing the <code>void</code> keyword everywhere when programming in C#.</p>

<p>Let&rsquo;s talk about it.</p>

<p>Every method performs actions using the data variables and members defined within a class. After performing those actions the method has to return the results of those actions or sometimes not return anything.</p>

<p><code>void</code> keyword is used when you don&rsquo;t want a method to return anything to the calling method/function. And when you want to return something using a method then you will have to specify the return data type of that method.</p>

<p><strong>Example:</strong></p>

<p><em>Note: Method names used in these examples are for educational purpose only. :P</em></p>

<pre><code>Public void IDontReturnAnything(){
    Console.WriteLine("Hello"); 
}

Public string IReturnAStringValue()
    return "Hello";
}

Public string IReturnAIntValue()
    return 143;
}
</code></pre>

<h2>Methods with Parameters and Arguments</h2>

<p>One or more variables declared with the Method Signature are called Parameters.</p>

<p>For example:</p>

<p><code>public double FindArea(int length, int width) { }</code></p>

<p>In the above given example <code>int length</code> and <code>int width</code> are parameters declared for the <code>FindArea()</code></p>

<p>When a method is declared with parameters then it means that method can accept input values or in other words it can accept arguments.</p>

<p>The values which we pass to method parameters are called <code>Arguments</code>.</p>

<p>While calling the <code>FindArea()</code> method we can pass the values as argument which the <code>FindArea()</code> method can use for processing like this <code>FindArea(3,4)</code>.</p>

<h2>this Keyword</h2>

<p><code>this</code> keyword in C# is used to access the class level members and data.</p>

<p>In a C# class there are different types of variables.</p>

<ul>
<li>Class level variables (Global to the whole class)</li>
<li>Method level parameter variables (Local to that method only which a method can return)</li>
</ul>


<p>For example:</p>

<p>You have declared a class level variable as <code>int age;</code> and method level parameter variable as <code>int age</code>.</p>

<p>To access class level age use <code>this.age</code> and for method level parameter variable use <code>age</code>.</p>

<pre><code>public class Employee
{
    public int age;

    // this is a parameterized constructor with age as parameter and initializing the class level age variable 
    // using the this keyword
    public Employee(int age)
    {
        // Here we are using this.age to access the class level variables and then assigning the input value of age
       // coming from the age parameter of the constructor
        this.age = age;
    }

    public DisplayEmployeeAage()
    {
        Console.WriteLine("Age is = " + age);
    }
}
</code></pre>

<h2>Object-Oriented Programming</h2>

<p>Any programming language which follows 3 rules of OOP is called a Object-Oriented Programming Language.</p>

<p><strong>Rules for OOP:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Encapsulation : Data Hiding</li>
<li>Polymorphism : Overloading and Overriding</li>
<li>Inheritance : Abstract classes and Interfaces</li>
</ul>


<p>Let&rsquo;s discuss each of these types in detail.</p>

<p><strong>Encapsulation</strong></p>

<p>Encapsulation is the concept of writing programs with data and methods that act on the data.</p>

<p>With encapsulation also comes another concept called Data Hiding. In data hiding we keep the data safe within the class and only accessible within the class. Now, that doesn&rsquo;t mean we wont be able to access the class data outside it. Yes we can access the data using public methods declared within a class.</p>

<p>Data hiding concept can be applied by using access modifiers in front of classes, member variables and methods.</p>

<p><em>Commonly used access modifiers:</em></p>

<ul>
<li>public : accessible at class, sub-class and project level</li>
<li>protected : accessible at class and sub-class level</li>
<li>private : accessible at class level only</li>
</ul>


<p>Example:</p>

<pre><code>public class Sample
{
    private int age;
    public int salary { get; private set; }

    public int DisplaySalary()
    {
        return this.salary;
    }

    public void SetData(int age, int salary)
    {
        this.age = age;
        this.salary = salary;
    }

    public void DisplayData()
    {
        Console.Write("age is = " + age);
        Console.Write("salary is = " + salary);
    }
}

public class TestSample
{
    static void Main()
    {
        Sample sample = new Sample();
        sample.SetData(2, 333);
        sample.DisplayData();

        //the age variable of the sample cannot be accessed here
        // is inaccessible due to protection level
        // sample.age;
        // this is encapsulation and data hiding

        Console.Write("\n");

        Console.Write("salary is = " + sample.DisplaySalary());

        Console.ReadLine();
    }
}
</code></pre>

<p>In order to implement data hiding we can use <code>getter</code> and <code>setter</code> to limited read and write access to a particular data member in a class.</p>

<p>In this example we have used <code>get</code> and <code>private set</code> for the salary property <code>public int salary { get; private set; }</code>.</p>

<p><code>get</code> means <code>salary</code> property can be accessed outside of the <code>Sample</code> class and <code>private set</code> means <code>salary</code> property data can be set within the <code>Sample</code> class only and not from outside of the class.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Learn C# in 7 Days : Day 1]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.abhishekluv.in/blog/2016/04/09/learn-csharp-in-7-days-day-1/"/>
    <updated>2016-04-09T07:07:42+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://www.abhishekluv.in/blog/2016/04/09/learn-csharp-in-7-days-day-1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Learning C# for beginners can be little difficult in the first place. But it isn&rsquo;t that difficult.</p>

<p>When starting to learn C# you should start with the basics and not get into the deep rabbit hole of it.</p>

<p>This is Day 1 of Learn C# in 7 Days.</p>

<p>Let&rsquo;s begin&hellip;</p>

<!-- more -->


<h2>Things you&rsquo;ll need to get started</h2>

<ul>
<li>PC</li>
<li>Visual Studio Express or Community Edition</li>
<li>Interest to learn C#</li>
</ul>


<h2>Hello World Program</h2>

<p>Every programming language is made up by using words and letters known as Keywords.</p>

<p>While programming we use <code>letters</code> and <code>words</code> to form <code>expressions and statements</code> and then those <code>statements</code> can be used within isolated function bodies called as <code>methods</code>.</p>

<pre><code>    class ExampleHelloWorld
    {
        static void Main()
        {
            Console.WriteLine("Hello World");
        }
    }
</code></pre>

<p>In the above given example, <code>class</code>, <code>static</code>, <code>void</code> are keywords and <code>Main()</code> is a method defined by the end user which acts as the entry point for the <code>HelloWorld</code> program.</p>

<p>C# is an object-oriented programming language. We won’t be going into the topic of <code>Classes</code> and <code>Objects</code> as of now.</p>

<p>Let&rsquo;s dissect the above give example.</p>

<p><code>Console</code> is a C# class coming from the <code>System</code> namespace.</p>

<p>Object oriented programming is about creating objects from classes and then using variables and calling methods of those objects.</p>

<p>Similarly in the above given example <code>Console</code> is a class which has a method called <code>WriteLine</code> which prints a value or any data on the console.</p>

<p>Now, How and what will the <code>WriteLine</code> method print on the console? It won’t do anything on its own.</p>

<p>We need to instruct the <code>WriteLine</code> method what to print on the screen and we can do that by passing data to the method known as <code>arguments</code>.</p>

<pre><code>Console.WriteLine("Hello World");
</code></pre>

<p>in the above line of code we are passing a <code>string</code> i.e. &ldquo;Hello World&rdquo; to the <code>WriteLine</code> method. It’s the job of the <code>WriteLine</code> method to print the given data via arguments on the console screen.</p>

<h2>Comments in CSharp</h2>

<p>Code without comments and documentation is bad code.</p>

<p>Comments are lines of text which gives information about the flow of the program and what does a method do when it’s called.</p>

<p>There are three types of comments:</p>

<ul>
<li>Single line comments</li>
<li>Multi-Line comments</li>
<li>XML Documentation comments</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Single-Line Comments</strong></p>

<pre><code>// this is variable with int data type
int myAge = 28;
</code></pre>

<p><strong>Multi-Line Comments</strong></p>

<pre><code>/* 
This is a multi line comments
You can write whatever you want
 */
</code></pre>

<p><strong>XML Documentation Comments</strong></p>

<pre><code>    /// &lt;summary&gt;
    /// This is the Main Method. It is an entry point for our application
    /// &lt;/summary&gt;
    static void Main()
    {
        string firstName = "Abhishek";

        string lastName = " Luv";

        string fullName = firstName + lastName;

        Console.WriteLine(fullName);
    }
</code></pre>

<p>XML documentation comments are used to write documentations for classes and methods in C#.</p>

<p>These XML comments are then used by Visual Studio to provide us information using Intellisense.</p>

<p>To write a XML comment just press <code>/</code> 3 times on any class or method.</p>

<h2>Data Types in CSharp</h2>

<p>Every programs needs memory and space to store data before it performs any operations and actions on the data.</p>

<p>Every value has a data type associated with it.</p>

<p>For example:</p>

<ul>
<li>A word like <code>Abhishek</code> will be of type <code>string</code> in C#</li>
<li>A numeric value like <code>12345</code> will be of type <code>int</code> in C#</li>
<li>A true or false value will be of type <code>bool</code> in C#</li>
<li>A numeric value like <code>233.33</code> will be of type <code>float</code> in C#
and so on&hellip;</li>
</ul>


<h2>Commonly used Data Types in CSharp</h2>

<ul>
<li>int : for numeric values</li>
<li>long : for larger numeric values</li>
<li>float : single-precision</li>
<li>double : double-precision</li>
<li>decimal : for very very very large numeric values</li>
<li>string : for storing words and text</li>
<li>bool : for storing true or false values</li>
</ul>


<h2>Declaring Variables using Data Types</h2>

<p>int example:</p>

<pre><code>data-type variable-name = variable-value;

int valueForA = 1200;
</code></pre>

<p>string example:</p>

<pre><code>string myName = "Abhishek Luv";
</code></pre>

<p>bool example:</p>

<pre><code>bool IsAvailable = true;
</code></pre>

<h2>Arithmetic Operators in CSharp</h2>

<ul>
<li>(+) : For addition</li>
<li>(-) : for subtraction</li>
<li>(*) : multiplication</li>
<li>/ : division</li>
<li>% : modulus</li>
<li>++ : increment</li>
<li>&ndash; : decrement</li>
</ul>


<p>These are the basic arithmetic operators used in C#. Let’s look at some sample code.</p>

<h2>Relational Operators in CSharp</h2>

<ul>
<li>(>) : Greater than</li>
<li>(&lt;) : Less than</li>
<li>(>=) : Greater than or equal to</li>
<li>(&lt;=) : Less than or equal to</li>
<li>(!=) : Not equal to</li>
<li>(==) : Equal to</li>
</ul>


<h2>Adding Number using in CSharp</h2>

<pre><code>    static void Main()
    {
        int a = 10; 
        int b = 20;

        int sum;

        // here we have used + operator for addition
        sum = a + b; 

        Console.WriteLine(sum);
    }
</code></pre>

<h2>Joining two string values using + Operator</h2>

<p>We can use the same + operator to join two string values in C#.</p>

<pre><code>    static void Main()
    {
        string firstName = "Abhishek";

        string lastName = " Luv";

        // here we have used + operator for joining two string values

        string fullName = firstName + lastName;

        Console.WriteLine(fullName);
    }
</code></pre>

<h2>Playing with If Else If Statement</h2>

<pre><code>    static void Main()
    {
        PlayingWithIf(20, 20);
    }

    static void PlayingWithIf(int x, int y)
    {
        if (x &lt; y)
        {
            Console.WriteLine("x is less than y");
        }

        else if (x &gt; y)
        {
            Console.WriteLine("x is greater than y");
        }

        else if (x == y)
        {
            Console.WriteLine("x is equal to y");
        }

        else
        {
            Console.WriteLine("invalid numbers");
        }
    }
</code></pre>

<p>In this example, we have a static void method called <code>PlayingWithIf</code> which uses <code>If Else If</code> statements with relational operators to print the desired output on the console screen. Don&rsquo;t worry about what is <code>static</code> and <code>void</code>. We&rsquo;ll come to that.</p>

<pre><code>if(x &lt; y) // if x is less than y then print "x is less than y"

else if(x &gt; y) // if x is greater than y then print "x is greater than y"

else if(x == y) // if x is equal to y then print "x is equal to y"

else....
</code></pre>

<p>Notice that the <code>PlayingWithIf</code> method takes in two <code>arguments</code> i.e. whenever the <code>PlayingWithIf</code> method is called we will have to provide two arguments or two values to the method.</p>

<pre><code>    static void Main()
    {
        PlayingWithIf(20, 20);
    }
</code></pre>

<p>Here, we are calling the <code>PlayingWithIf</code> method in our Main method with two arguments (20,20).</p>

<p>It’s always better to write a standalone method than stuffing the entire Main method with code.</p>

<h2>For Loop Statements</h2>

<p>A For loop statement is used for looping to perform actions based on the initial value and the test condition declared within a For loop.</p>

<p>For example: Lets print numbers 10 to 0 using a for loop</p>

<pre><code>    static void Main()
    {
        for (int i = 10; i &gt;= 0; i--)
        {
            Console.WriteLine(i);
        }
    }
</code></pre>

<p>In this example, we have declared a initial variable <code>int i</code> with a value of <code>10</code> i.e. we are saying the For loop to set the initial value equal to 10.</p>

<p><code>i &gt;= 0;</code> is the condition defined within the loop. This instructs the for loop to keep running the loop until the value <code>i</code> is greater than or equal to 0.</p>

<p><code>i--</code> is the action to performed by the for loop for us.</p>

<p>As the loop runs with the help of <code>i--</code> the value <code>i</code> is decremented by -1 till the condition <code>i &gt;= 0</code> is met.</p>

<h2>While Loop</h2>

<p>let’s look at the same example using a while loop in C#.</p>

<pre><code>    static void Main()
    {
        int i = 10; // initial variables declared

        while (i &gt;= 0) // test condition
        {
            Console.WriteLine(i);
            i--; // action to be performed every time the loop runs
        }
    }
</code></pre>

<p>In a While loop, we declare the initial variable and value outside the loop.</p>

<p>While loop starts with a test condition and then the body of the loop within curly braces {}.</p>

<p>Here, the condition is to keep running the loop until the value of i is greater than or equal to zero.</p>

<p>And the action to be performed in within the while loop i.e. <code>i--</code>.</p>

<h2>Do..While loop</h2>

<p>Do..While loop is very similar to the While loop but with only two differences.</p>

<p><strong>First Difference</strong></p>

<p>In a Do..While loop the statements inside the body of the loop are executed once before any conditions are met or the actions are performed by the loop.</p>

<p>For example:</p>

<pre><code>    static void Main()
    {
        int i = 0;

        do
        {
            Console.WriteLine(i);
            i++;
        } while (i &lt;= 10);
    }
</code></pre>

<p><strong>Second Difference</strong></p>

<p>Here, Initial value of <code>i</code> is 0. In a Do..While loop the condition is checked at the end of the loop and in a While loop at the beginning of the loop</p>

<p>And the actions <code>i++</code> is performed within the Do loop.</p>

<h2>Commonly used Logical Operators in CSharp</h2>

<ul>
<li>&amp;&amp; : logical AND</li>
<li>|| : logical OR</li>
</ul>


<p>Example:</p>

<pre><code>    static void Main()
    {
        CheckNumbers(10, 20);
    }

    static void CheckNumbers(int x, int y)
    {
        if (x &gt;= 0 &amp;&amp; y &gt;= 0)
        {
            Console.WriteLine("both numbers positive");
        }

        else if (x &gt;= 0 || y &gt;= 0)
        {
            Console.WriteLine("at least one num is positive");
        }
        else
        {
            Console.WriteLine("both are negative");
        }
    }
</code></pre>

<p>In the above given code, we have a method called <code>CheckNumbers</code>.</p>

<p>The <code>CheckNumbers</code> method takes in two arguments to check whether the numbers are positive or negative.</p>

<pre><code>if (x &gt;= 0 &amp;&amp; y &gt;= 0) 
// 10 &gt;= 0 &amp;&amp; 20 &gt;= 0 
// Result will be : both numbers are positive
</code></pre>

<p>Condition <code>10 &gt;= 0</code> will return true and <code>20 &gt;= 0</code> will also return true. So, true * true is true i.e. both numbers are positive.</p>

<p>Similarly OR <code>||</code> is used check at least one positive number and the <code>else</code> block executes when both the numbers are negative.</p>

<h2>Switch Case Statement</h2>

<p>Switch case statements are very similar to If statements. Switch case can be used with any data type.</p>

<p>In a switch case statement, we provide a value which it uses to compare with the cases defined within the switch statement and display appropriate results on the console.</p>

<p><em>Note: Case declared within a switch case statement has to be constant</em></p>

<pre><code>    static void Main(string[] args)
    {
        PlayingWithSwitchCase("three");
    }

    static void PlayingWithSwitchCase(string j)
    {
        switch (j)
        {
            case "two":
                Console.WriteLine("you entered four in words");
                break;
            case "three":
                Console.WriteLine("you entered three in words");
                break;
            default:
                Console.WriteLine("error");
                break;
        }
    }
</code></pre>

<h2>Arrays in CSharp</h2>

<p>Arrays are used to store a collection of data of similar data types.</p>

<p>For example: If you want to declared 5 int variable how will you do it?</p>

<p>Like this right?</p>

<pre><code>int a = 1;
int b = 2;
int c = 3;
int d = 4;
int e = 5;
</code></pre>

<p>Now, this is a lot of code. It’s better to use arrays to store 5 int values than using 5 different int variables.</p>

<p><strong>Declaring Arrays</strong></p>

<pre><code>int[] arrayName = new int[sizeofthearray];

int[] intArray = new int[5];
</code></pre>

<p>Now int[5] means that this array can hold 5 values. Values or data within an array can be accessed using an index.</p>

<p>For example:</p>

<pre><code>intArray[0], intArray[1] and so on...
</code></pre>

<p><em>Note: Index of an array starts from value 0. i.e. If you want to access the 5th value then you need to use intArray[4]</em></p>

<p><strong>Looping over an array to display data using For Looping</strong></p>

<pre><code>    for (int i = 0; i &lt; intArray.Length; i++)
    {
        Console.WriteLine(intArray[i]);
    }
</code></pre>

<p>The for loop uses the <code>intArray.Length</code> of the array to define a test condition for the loop.</p>

<p><strong>Looping over an array using ForEach loop</strong></p>

<pre><code>    foreach (int tempArrayValue in intArray)
    {
        Console.WriteLine(tempArrayValue);
    }
</code></pre>

<p>The ForEach loop uses a <code>tempArrayValue</code> variable to hold the array values one by one and display it on the console screen.</p>

<h2>Strings in CSharp</h2>

<p>Anything within double quotes <code>"Abhishek Luv"</code> in C# is a string.</p>

<p><strong>Declaring a string</strong></p>

<pre><code>string myName = "Abhishek Luv";
</code></pre>

<p><strong>Declaring an array of string</strong></p>

<pre><code>string[] allListOfName = { "Abhishek", "Abhijeet","Akshay" };
</code></pre>

<p><strong>Commonly used String functions</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>ToUpper()</li>
<li>ToLower()</li>
<li>SubString()</li>
<li>IndexOf</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Looping over an array of string using foreach loop</strong></p>

<pre><code>foreach (string names in allListOfName)
{
   Console.WriteLine(names);
}
</code></pre>

<p><em>Day 1 over</em></p>

<p>Stay Tuned.</p>

<p>Take Care!</p>

<p>Abhishek Luv</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Orchard CMS Theme Development Course Is FREE Now]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.abhishekluv.in/blog/2016/04/08/orchard-cms-theme-development-course-is-free-now/"/>
    <updated>2016-04-08T17:18:12+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://www.abhishekluv.in/blog/2016/04/08/orchard-cms-theme-development-course-is-free-now</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Access to Orchard CMS Theme Development course is FREE and open to all.</p>

<!-- more -->




<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/videoseries?list=PL8AwaH3ssiARImeICwvOavU_Gna-Xza_7" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Orchard CMS Recipes Course Is FREE Now]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.abhishekluv.in/blog/2016/04/08/orchard-cms-recipes-course-is-free-now/"/>
    <updated>2016-04-08T17:17:56+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://www.abhishekluv.in/blog/2016/04/08/orchard-cms-recipes-course-is-free-now</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Access to Orchard CMS Recipes course is FREE and open to all.</p>

<!-- more -->




<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/videoseries?list=PL8AwaH3ssiASskvNYC69I-FKr3kjcBo8X" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Orchard CMS Workflows Course Is FREE Now]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.abhishekluv.in/blog/2016/04/08/orchard-cms-workflows-course-is-free-now/"/>
    <updated>2016-04-08T17:17:46+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://www.abhishekluv.in/blog/2016/04/08/orchard-cms-workflows-course-is-free-now</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Access to Orchard CMS Workflows course is FREE and open to all.</p>

<!-- more -->




<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/videoseries?list=PL8AwaH3ssiASR5GeZtPvKnyOAGogyMnjt" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
