<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: 2016 | Abhishek Luv]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.abhishekluv.in/blog/categories/2016/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.abhishekluv.in/"/>
  <updated>2016-02-07T06:48:40+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://www.abhishekluv.in/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Abhishek Luv]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Monthly Review : January 2016]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.abhishekluv.in/blog/2016/01/29/monthly-review-january-2016/"/>
    <updated>2016-01-29T22:08:14+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://www.abhishekluv.in/blog/2016/01/29/monthly-review-january-2016</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is my first monthly review. Keeping a note of every task I have really helped myself to stay more focused and measure my progress in a better way.</p>

<p><em>As I had mentioned in one of my <a href="/blog/2015/12/21/plans-for-year-2016/">previous post</a> that I will be keeping track of every task I do and blog about it online.</em></p>

<!-- more -->


<h2>Review for January 2016</h2>

<ul>
<li>Stopped using Facebook :P</li>
<li>Finished listening to an audio book &ldquo;Living Health&rdquo; by Tony Robbins</li>
<li>Launched <a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCAQxeMbUaKePrVE3wbNZxjg">Orchard Beginner YouTube channel</a></li>
<li>Completed and Uploaded <a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCAQxeMbUaKePrVE3wbNZxjg/playlists?view=1&amp;flow=list&amp;sort=da">3 course modules for Orchard Beginner</a></li>
<li>Finished reading a book called <a href="http://www.amazon.in/Your-Erroneous-Zones-Step-Step/dp/0060919760">&ldquo;Your Erroneous Zone&rdquo;</a> by Wayne dyer</li>
<li>Integrated <a href="https://www.instamojo.com/">InstaMojo</a> with Develop2Deploy for accepting and receiving payments</li>
<li>Completed 2 courses for Develop2Deploy(Sorry the Website and Courses are still offline and underdevelopment)</li>
<li>Read a 35 page book <a href="http://www.amazon.in/gp/product/B00FIZ5G3I?psc=1&amp;redirect=true&amp;ref_=oh_aui_d_detailpage_o00_">&ldquo;The Opinionated Software Developer: What Twenty-Five Years of Slinging Code Has Taught Me&rdquo;</a> by Shawn Wildermuth</li>
</ul>


<p>Stay tuned.</p>

<p>Take care!</p>

<p>Abhishek Luv</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ways in Which You Can Contribute to Open Source Projects]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.abhishekluv.in/blog/2016/01/28/ways-in-which-you-can-contribute-to-open-source-projects/"/>
    <updated>2016-01-28T16:49:57+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://www.abhishekluv.in/blog/2016/01/28/ways-in-which-you-can-contribute-to-open-source-projects</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I love open source projects and contributing to open source projects has helped me in many ways.</p>

<h2>Benefits of contributing to open source projects:</h2>

<ul>
<li>Opportunity to meet new people online</li>
<li>Community owners and contributors will trust you without meeting you in person</li>
<li>Community appreciations</li>
<li>and many more&hellip;</li>
</ul>


<p>Never contributed to any open source project?</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>No problem. Find an open source project in your area of interest and start contributing.</p>

<p>Let me share my contributing experience and how I started contributing to an open source project called &ldquo;Orchard&rdquo;.</p>

<p>BTW.</p>

<p>Orchard CMS is a free, open source, community-focused Content Management System built on the ASP.NET MVC platform.</p>


<p>Orchard is delivered under the .NET Foundation <a href="http://www.dotnetfoundation.org/orchard">http://www.dotnetfoundation.org/orchard</a>. For more info on Orchard visit the official website <a href="http://www.orchardproject.net/">http://www.orchardproject.net/</a>
and for more Orchard CMS tutorials subscribe to <a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCAQxeMbUaKePrVE3wbNZxjg">Orchard Beginner YouTube channel.</a></p>


<p>Let&rsquo;s talk about the ways in which you can contribute to open source projects.</p>

<ul>
<li>Write documentations</li>
<li>Create tutorials</li>
<li>Create premium tutorials</li>
<li>Contribute source code or Help find/fix bugs</li>
<li>Spread the word and your knowledge</li>
<li>Appreciating the community and not be a jerk</li>
<li>Interview other open source contributors and share knowledge</li>
</ul>


<h2>Write documentations</h2>

<p>Most open source projects lack good documentation and this is an opportunity for you as a newbie or an experienced developer to put in some efforts and start writing documentations for your favourite open source project.</p>

<p>Most of the open source documentations are written in .md Markdown so make sure to learn Markdown before starting to contribute/fix documentations.</p>

<p>Community owners and members really appreciate genuine contributors and might give write/push access to the documentation repository.</p>

<p>For example:</p>

<p><a href="http://docs.orchardproject.net/Contributors">http://docs.orchardproject.net/Contributors</a></p>

<h2>Create tutorials</h2>

<p>After writing some documentation and gaining some experience with an open source project you can move to the next level and start creating video tutorials which will ultimately help new community members and shorten the learning curve.</p>

<p>Creating tutorials and uploading them on YouTube comes with added bonus i.e. <a href="http://orchardbeginner.com/">more traffic to your own blog or website</a> which can bring in some nice exposure for you as a contributor/developer.</p>

<p>For example:</p>

<p>It makes me feel so appreciated when other developers and contributors share my tutorial and course links on Stackoverflow.</p>

<p><a href="http://stackoverflow.com/a/11452276">http://stackoverflow.com/a/11452276</a></p>

<h2>Create premium tutorials</h2>

<p>With uploading free tutorials on YouTube you can even start selling premium tutorials and courses via online platforms like Udemy.</p>

<p>For example:</p>

<p>After creating my first Orchard tutorial series I created 2 premium courses and the response I got from the community and subscribers were astonishing. All of my Orchard courses are listed on the official documentation website of Orchard.</p>

<p><a href="http://docs.orchardproject.net/Documentation/Orchard-TV">http://docs.orchardproject.net/Documentation/Orchard-TV</a></p>

<h2>Contribute source code or Help find/fix bugs</h2>

<p>The number one way to help out is find/fix bugs for your favourite open source project. Found a bug fix it or let other community contributors know about it.</p>

<p>Most of the open source projects are hosted on GitHub so make sure to learn Git and GitHub before creating issues/pull requests for your favourite open source project.</p>

<p>For example:</p>

<p>The community owners and members appreciated my contribution with a shout out.</p>

<p><a href="http://docs.orchardproject.net/Documentation/Orchard-1-9.Release-Notes#Contributors">http://docs.orchardproject.net/Documentation/Orchard-1-9.Release-Notes#Contributors</a></p>

<h2>Spread the word and your knowledge</h2>

<p>You can go and tell the world about your favourite open source project. Tweet about it. Blog about it. Just help get the word out and make the project more popular.</p>

<p><a href="http://orchardbeginner.com/">http://orchardbeginner.com/</a></p>

<h2>Appreciating the community and not be a jerk</h2>

<p>Never ever act like a jerk while interacting with the community contributors and members. Never try to take them for granted.</p>

<h2>Interview other open source contributors and share knowledge</h2>

<p>You can even interview other contributors of your favourite open source projects and share the knowledge.</p>

<p>If you have any other ideas on how to contribute, please share them below in the comments.</p>

<p>Stay tuned.</p>

<p>Take care!</p>

<p>Abhishek Luv</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Important Things to Do When Installing Orchard CMS for the First Time]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.abhishekluv.in/blog/2016/01/27/important-things-to-do-when-installing-orchard-cms-for-the-first-time/"/>
    <updated>2016-01-27T22:08:24+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://www.abhishekluv.in/blog/2016/01/27/important-things-to-do-when-installing-orchard-cms-for-the-first-time</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Important things to do when installing <em>Orchard CMS</em> for the first time.</p>

<!-- more -->


<ul>
<li>Giving write permissions to the following folders(App_Data,Modules,Themes,Media) applicable for IIS/Web Hosts only and not for WebMatrix and IIS express.</li>
<li>Installing Orchard with a pre-defined recipe or with a custom recipe (optional)</li>
<li>Remove Home page title and text</li>
<li>Configure your site settings properly</li>
<li>Configure your cache settings properly</li>
<li>Configure the email module with valid SMTP details (so that the reset password works when you forget your password)</li>
<li>Configure Antispam modules</li>
<li>Enable warmup module for performance boost(Orchard creates static versions of specified pages)</li>
<li>Hide the meta published part if you want to hide the published dates for pages using placement.info file in your custom theme</li>
<li>Check if the version you&rsquo;re using is the latest version.</li>
<li>Assigning administrator roles to the admin user</li>
<li>Adding an email address for the admin user</li>
<li>Enabling database and file system output cache(Optional/If required)</li>
<li>Enabling Audit trail module to monitor backend activities on your website(optional)</li>
<li>Remember to turn off unwanted modules</li>
<li>Copy the settings.txt file and save it in a secure place (for future use/backup)</li>
<li>Enabling import/export and creating a recipe of your website (for future use/backup)</li>
</ul>


<p>New to Orchard CMS?</p>


<p>Orchard CMS is a free, open source, community-focused Content Management System built on the ASP.NET MVC platform.</p>


<p>Orchard is delivered under the .NET Foundation <a href="http://www.dotnetfoundation.org/orchard">http://www.dotnetfoundation.org/orchard</a>. For more info on Orchard visit the official website <a href="http://www.orchardproject.net/">http://www.orchardproject.net/</a>
and for more Orchard CMS tutorials subscribe to <a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCAQxeMbUaKePrVE3wbNZxjg">Orchard Beginner YouTube channel.</a></p>


<p>Stay tuned.</p>

<p>Take care!</p>

<p>Abhishek Luv</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Orchard Beginner Module 1 : Getting Started (Completed)]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.abhishekluv.in/blog/2016/01/26/orchard-beginner-module-1-getting-started-completed/"/>
    <updated>2016-01-26T13:33:24+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://www.abhishekluv.in/blog/2016/01/26/orchard-beginner-module-1-getting-started-completed</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Orchard Beginner Module 1 : Getting Started completed.</p>

<p>Orchard CMS Tutorials brought to you by Orchard Beginner <a href="http://orchardbeginner.com/">http://orchardbeginner.com/</a></p>

<p><em>Note: As I had mentioned in one of my <a href="/blog/2015/12/21/plans-for-year-2016/">previous post</a> that I will be keeping track of every task I do and blog about it online.</em></p>

<!-- more -->




<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/CbBuiHj0Qkg?list=PL8AwaH3ssiATad095YNAoaIxHVkoh4Yky" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>




<p>New to Orchard CMS?</p>


<p>Orchard CMS is a free, open source, community-focused Content Management System built on the ASP.NET MVC platform.</p>


<p>Orchard is delivered under the .NET Foundation <a href="http://www.dotnetfoundation.org/orchard">http://www.dotnetfoundation.org/orchard</a>. For more info on Orchard visit the official website <a href="http://www.orchardproject.net/">http://www.orchardproject.net/</a>
and for more Orchard CMS tutorials subscribe to <a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCAQxeMbUaKePrVE3wbNZxjg">our Orchard Beginner YouTube channel</a> or bookmark Orchard Beginner website for future reference.</p>


<p>Stay tuned.</p>

<p>Take care!</p>

<p>Abhishek Luv</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Standing and Sitting With Pomodoro Technique]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.abhishekluv.in/blog/2016/01/13/standing-and-sitting-with-pomodoro-technique/"/>
    <updated>2016-01-13T17:31:42+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://www.abhishekluv.in/blog/2016/01/13/standing-and-sitting-with-pomodoro-technique</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Standing and Sitting with Pomodoro Technique.</p>

<p>This week I decided to experiment and make a custom standing desk for myself.</p>




<!-- more -->




<p><em>As I had mentioned in one of my <a href="http://www.abhishekluv.in/blog/2015/12/21/plans-for-year-2016/">previous post</a> that I will be keeping track of every task I do and blog about it online.</em></p>




<p>At this moment the setup looks quite messy with a lot of wires hanging around.</p>




<h2>Things used to setup the standing desk</h2>




<p><em>Only two things.</em></p>




<ul>
<li>A Wooden adjustable study table</li>
<li>Some books to adjust the height of the wooden study table</li>
</ul>




<h2>Cost</h2>




<p>Just 900/- INR i.e. $15</p>




<p><img src="" data-src="http://s3-ap-southeast-1.amazonaws.com/d2dstaticresources/abhishek/Standing+Desk.JPG" title="Abhishek Luv's Custom Standing Desk" alt="&quot;Abhishek Luv's Custom Standing Desk&quot;" /></p>


<p>Why a standing desk? Because too much of sitting is bad.</p>

<h2>What happens if you stand too much?</h2>

<ul>
<li>It can cause leg pain</li>
<li>It can cause back pain</li>
<li>It can make your legs sore</li>
</ul>


<h2>What happens if you sit too much?</h2>

<ul>
<li>It can affect the flow of blood and oxygen in your body</li>
<li>It can become the cause of your obesity</li>
<li>It can cause you headaches, legs, arms and wrist numbness</li>
</ul>


<p>We need to strike a balance between standing, sitting and doing activities like stretching, squatting, doing vital deep diaphragmatic breathing, and drinking plenty of water which can help us lose those fat sitting on our belly.</p>

<p>Ever heard of Pomodoro technique?</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s a technique where you work with time and not against time by taking short breaks in between while doing your work.</p>

<p>It can help you manage distractions and create a better work/life balance.</p>

<p>Now should we stand or sit while working? It&rsquo;s not a question about standing or sitting. Moving more is probably better than standing or sitting.</p>

<h2>Better solution</h2>

<p>A better solution is to use Pomodoro technique with standing and sitting while working.</p>

<p>Example:</p>

<ul>
<li>Standing for 25mins and Sitting for 5mins</li>
<li>Sitting for 50mins and Standing for 10mins</li>
<li>Note: Don&rsquo;t forget to include squatting and stretching and having plenty of water while you stand or sit</li>
</ul>


<p>The key is to do some activity every day.</p>

<ul>
<li>A walk to and from work</li>
<li>or taking the stairs</li>
</ul>


<p>Stay healthy, Stay fit!</p>

<p>Stay tuned!</p>




<p>Take care!</p>




<p>Abhishek Luv</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
